The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Country of Suzaku
Greetings, Third Senior Sister.
Bai Xue\NImmortal’s Path Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
Is this fellow cultivator Ceng Niu ?
I am a disciple of the Immortal’s Path Sect,
Bai Xue.
Master said you are new to Suzaku,
so I will arrange everything for you.
Please...
The jade's description of the country of Suzaku was not detailed,
so seeing it with my own eyes
is truly extraordinary.
I thought Ceng Niu had unparalleled talent
but it seems he is nothing special.
Fellow cultivator Ceng Niu,
the land beneath your feet
is the largest continent on the entire planet Suzaku,
the Suzaku continent.
It only has 4 cultivation countries.
They are Suzaku,
Azure Dragon,
Thousand Illusions,
and the Pilu country.
Our country of Suzaku,
the only rank 6 cultivation country on planet Suzaku,
is located at the center of the Suzaku continent
and holds a dominant position.
It is said that even mortals born in Suzaku
consider themselves superior to everyone else.
Looks like it's true.
What are the sects in Suzaku ?
Our country of Suzaku is divided into the Heavenly Jade Sect,
the Earth Soul Sect.
and the Immortal’s Path Sect.
Each has an Ascendant ancestor overseeing it.
They are governed by the 14th generation Suzaku,
Zhuque Zi.
What is his cultivation level ?
Zhuque Zi
is the only
Peak Late stage Ascendant cultivator on planet Suzaku.
But he rarely appears...
In all these years, I have only seen him once.
Heavenly Jade sect\NCountry of Suzaku
This is the Heavenly Jade Sect,
Junior Sister Red Butterfly is a disciple of this sect.
I have heard that
Master intends to recruit you into the Immortal's Path Sect.
Your duel with her is set in 7 days.
Are you confident ?
Not at all.
Fellow cultivator Ceng doesn’t have to be modest.
For now, you will stay at the Immortal's Path Sect.
Once Master is done cultivating,
he will meet you.
Immortal Path's Sect\NCountry of Suzaku
Wang Lin's mansion\NImmortal Path's Sect
Wait a moment.
I've had this feeling of danger
since I entered Suzaku.
This place doesn’t feel like a residence
but more like a prison.
Since this duel cannot be avoided
I should first complete my map
to prepare for emergencies.
In the country of Suzaku
there are many people
that can kill me...
Not only did Zhuque Zi not pursue the matter of me severing Red Butterfly’s arm
but also sent us both to the two major sects...
What is he trying to do ?
Is he just choosing between the two of us
or does he have another scheme ?
This person can enter my room without me noticing...
He must be above Soul Transformation.
Li Yunlong\NImmortal Path's Sect Ancestor\NEarly stage Ascendant
Could he be
the Immortal Path's Sect Ancestor ?
Lose, Die.
Winning this duel
does not guarantee
my survival.
But losing it
means certain death.
Two Ascendant ancestors
have personally come to oversee the event.
Of course,
it's the duel between the prodigy Red Butterfly
and the rising star Ceng Niu.
Their duel
will surely be spectacular.
It’s about to start !
Paying respects to the Suzaku.
It’s starting...
Zhuque Zi\N14th generation Suzaku\NPeak Late stage Ascendant
Everyone, rise.
This person somewhat resembles the old man...
The Suzaku came personally ?
Are those the Suzaku's direct disciples ?
I am even more excited for today’s match
Liu Mei\NZhuque Zi's second disciple\NMiddle stage Soul Transformation
Qian Feng\NZhuque Zi's first disciple\NMiddle stage Soul Transformation
The duel
officially begins now !
Chu Yunfei\NHeavenly Jade Sect Ancestor\NEarly stage Ascendant
Training grounds\NCountry of Suzaku
Red Butterfly...
Ceng Niu,
prepare to die !
Red Butterfly’s cultivation is above mine.
Since I cannot kill her in one strike,
I must disrupt her Dao heart
and find an opportunity to attack.
This is an artifact that my Xue Yue country
has been refining for 500 years:
the Ice God.
I will make sure you die today !
Scarlet Swords
Attack !
Go !
Ceng Niu,
you lost.
You're wrong,
we are just getting started.
When Divine Retribution descends,
teleporting away is useless.
Red Butterfly...
you're dead !
Six return to one !
Although the puppets cannot stop the tribulation
they can tank some of its energy
to reduce its power.
Explode !
You forced me to do this !
Soul Lasher !
Soul Lasher
What kind of artifact is this ?!
What is that ?
With just one strike, Ceng Niu was severely injured...
So powerful !
This thing...
isn't it the treasure of your Heavenly Jade Sect ?
How did it end up in Red Butterfly's hands ?
I was careless in guarding it.
After this duel
I will investigate thoroughly
and give Suzaku an explanation.
Ceng Niu actually managed to summon a tribulation...
Thankfully, I gave the artifact to Junior Sister.
Otherwise, the consequences would have been unimaginable.
Let's see what else you can do.
This whip is too strange.
It can directly damage the soul.
I need time
to activate the God Slaying Chariot.
Now,
Let's see how long you can suppress
the curses I planted in you !
Curse !
Almost there
Now is the time !
God Slaying Chariot,
activate !
I once thought that
Ceng Niu was just an insignificant ant
unworthy of being compared to me.
With the Ice God
and my life artifact
killing Ceng Niu should've been as easy as stealing from a child.
But today's duel
is several times more difficult than in the Celestial Realm.
If it weren't for the Soul Lasher given by Feng Yushan,
I would have been defeated !
Now, the Ice God is extremely weak...
Could it be that
I really am losing to Ceng Niu ?!
Xu Liguo !
No...
I won't lose !
Ceng Niu,
I don’t mind giving up my chance to reach Soul Transformation
just to kill you !
Soul Splitting !
Ruthless Domain !
So this is the domain of a peak Soul Formation cultivator...
This Soul Splitting technique...
She was supposed to merge with the avatar to reach Soul Transformation...
It contains her lifetime of enlightenment about the Dao
and her Ruthless Domain.
Ceng Niu won't be able to withstand it.
This duel has drained my soul too much,
I can't break her domain anymore...
Emotions, come forth...
Tie Zhu...
Come here !
Come !
Senior,
I'm scared.
Wang Lin
Uncle Wang,
save me !
Wang Lin
Familial love,
romantic love,
hatred,
and appreciation
are all useless illusions !
Like these thorny vines,
they will eventually become a burden for your cultivation.
Sword of Wisdom
Ceng Niu,
I want you to witness
all your loved ones
leave you behind !
Sword of Wisdom,
sever !
Tie Zhu...
Enter the world to draw out emotions
then wield the Sword of Wisdom
to sever all emotions.
This is the Ruthless Domain.
Ceng Niu,
so you have finally severed your emotions aswell.
You've lost.
Now,
I will destroy your soul !
My son,
no matter what you have done
you must take care of yourself.
The heavens won't allow Wan'er to live.
Since you're here...
I have no regrets...
After cultivating in the Heaven Defying Bead for so long,
you've only barely reached the first layer of Qi Condensation.
I will fight back !
Uncle Wang !
Brother Ceng Niu,
either you understand or you don't.
This bead contains my Divine Sense.
Noooo !!!
Senior...
don't cry...
No,
you're wrong.
What ?!
The emotions of this world
cannot be severed
so easily.
Although the Sword of Wisdom is strong,
it can't cut through the reincarnation cycle.
After being pushed this far,
I have been enlightened.
Thank you for helping me realize
that even a heartless person
cannot escape the Life and Death reincarnation cycle.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.